<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Emacs on Javier Pacheco - Blog</title>
    <link>https://jpachecoxyz.github.io/tags/emacs/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Emacs on Javier Pacheco - Blog</description>
    <generator>Hugo</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 18:06:28 -0500</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://jpachecoxyz.github.io/tags/emacs/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Your blog in emacs.</title>
      <link>https://jpachecoxyz.github.io/posts/your-blog-in-emacs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 18:06:00 -0500</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jpachecoxyz.github.io/posts/your-blog-in-emacs/</guid>
      <description>What do you need?. In order to start developing your blog site within emacs you need to require ox-hugo, an emacs package for export your org files to a marckdown files. I&amp;rsquo;m not going to write about how to install ox-hugo because I asuming that you already knows how to install emacs packages.&#xA;Of course we are going to use hugo, so we also need it installed, so this is what we need:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Efetch.el</title>
      <link>https://jpachecoxyz.github.io/posts/efetch/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 13 Jan 2024 04:11:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://jpachecoxyz.github.io/posts/efetch/</guid>
      <description>Embrace a new level of Emacs mastery with efetch.el – a powerful and user-friendly Emacs Fetching Tool. Designed for enthusiasts who crave insights into their Emacs environment, efetch.el provides a seamless way to peek under the hood of your setup. With just a simple command, unlock a left-side buffer showcasing key details such as Emacs version, host information, user details, installed packages, active theme, and default font. Customizable and accessible, this tool not only delivers a quick snapshot of your Emacs configuration but also opens the door for collaborative enhancements.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
